<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on SimpleShapes | The home of David Adams</title>
    <link>https://simpleshapes.io/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on SimpleShapes | The home of David Adams</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://simpleshapes.io/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The red alert approach to product development</title>
      <link>https://simpleshapes.io/articles/the-red-alert-approach-to-product-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://simpleshapes.io/articles/the-red-alert-approach-to-product-development/</guid>
      <description>Launching new products is really hard. Each year around 30,000 new products are introduced, of these, 95% fail. Think about that for a second. You and your 19 closest friends all decide to launch your own products. Before long, only Bert is left standing, with a product that people actually want to buy. Stupid Bert.
I’ll say it again, launching new products is really, really hard. There are so many things you need to be doing, every day a new article tells you about a new thing that’s you aren’t doing that you absolutely must be doing to be successful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 takeaways from Shape Up</title>
      <link>https://simpleshapes.io/articles/5-takeaways-from-shape-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://simpleshapes.io/articles/5-takeaways-from-shape-up/</guid>
      <description>A couple of weeks back Ryan Singer from the Basecamp team released Shape Up: Stop Running in Circles and Ship Work that Matters. An in-depth look at how they do product development at Basecamp. From the first few pages, I was hooked. The approach answers several product development questions I’ve struggled to come up with good answers to in the past. Below are the things that stayed with me from the book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here goes nothing</title>
      <link>https://simpleshapes.io/articles/here-goes-nothing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://simpleshapes.io/articles/here-goes-nothing/</guid>
      <description>I’m going to attempt to write weekly.
Certainly, if not weekly, then fortnightly. I have 2 young daughters, I need to bake in some slack somewhere.
I’ve long been meaning to start writing properly. I’ve dipped in and out a little recently, but I’m hoping by drawing a starting line, I can make it a regular, deliberate practise. Who knows if it will stick.
Why? First of all, this is for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make your startup website work to get you customers</title>
      <link>https://simpleshapes.io/articles/make-your-startup-website-work-to-get-you-customers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://simpleshapes.io/articles/make-your-startup-website-work-to-get-you-customers/</guid>
      <description>As a startup, when you’re just getting started and launching your website, it’s really important to set it up to work for you. To turn visitors into customers.
To do this, it’s important to clearly state what they will be able to achieve with your help. For B2C products, it can be any range of social, productivity or life-quality benefits. With B2B it usually comes down to unlocking revenue potential.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking the product roadmap</title>
      <link>https://simpleshapes.io/articles/rethinking-the-product-roadmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 09:17:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://simpleshapes.io/articles/rethinking-the-product-roadmap/</guid>
      <description>There has always been something about traditional product roadmaps, especially gannt charts that has made me feel uneasy. I think it’s probably the false sense of control they can give you, if not used carefully. You can plot out some high level features/initiatives over an entire year and suddenly you have a tangible plan, a sense of control over the chaos.
In reality that’s all there is, a sense of control, not actual control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build and launch your startup landing page in a day, with little to no coding required</title>
      <link>https://simpleshapes.io/articles/building-your-landing-page-super-fast/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://simpleshapes.io/articles/building-your-landing-page-super-fast/</guid>
      <description>Building time In this guide, we’re going walk through how to build a landing page that for your new product in ~ 1 day. It will convey your core offering, enable potential users to sign up to a waitlist, and elicit feedback on product direction.
We’re going to use existing tools and shortcuts as much as possible. So will only need very minimal coding knowledge, I’ll walk you through any edits you might need to make.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to write effective content for your startup landing page</title>
      <link>https://simpleshapes.io/articles/writing-effective-landing-page-content/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 12:14:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://simpleshapes.io/articles/writing-effective-landing-page-content/</guid>
      <description>Define your goal and messaging When launching a new product, in the rush to get it ready, the marketing website often ends up getting pushed down the priority list. This is totally understandable, there is so much to do and so little time, it is an easy target for pushing back; you’re not launched yet, so it can wait. But this is an opportunity wasted. You could have a presence out there, starting to build a reputation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a successful MVP</title>
      <link>https://simpleshapes.io/articles/building-a-successful-mvp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://simpleshapes.io/articles/building-a-successful-mvp/</guid>
      <description>Since the success of the lean startup, most people in the start-up world and beyond are familiar with the concept of a minimum viable product (MVP).
However, it seems, in a lot of cases, teams miss the point of an MVP. There is a whole lot of subjectivity in the viable part. Viable for what? For who? Who gets to define this? More importantly it is far too easy to try to cram one more feature in, leading to a half-baked product that doesn&amp;rsquo;t fully know what it&amp;rsquo;s purpose is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nothing to see here</title>
      <link>https://simpleshapes.io/articles/nothing-to-see-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://simpleshapes.io/articles/nothing-to-see-here/</guid>
      <description>Oh, hello there This is the first post, I should delete it - but I don&amp;rsquo;t really want to 🙃.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>